<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-27T10:42:02+11:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Random notes</title><subtitle>Just an arbitrary collection of notes.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Covid tests</title><link href="/generic/2020/07/16/covid-tests.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Covid tests" /><published>2020-07-16T22:39:28+10:00</published><updated>2020-07-16T22:39:28+10:00</updated><id>/generic/2020/07/16/covid-tests</id><content type="html" xml:base="/generic/2020/07/16/covid-tests.html">&lt;p&gt;Time complexity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Best: $O(n)$&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Average: $O(n^2)$&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Worst: $O(n^2)$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space complexity: $O(1)$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tga.gov.au/covid-19-testing-australia-information-health-professionals&quot;&gt;Covid tests TGA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tga.gov.au/covid-19-test-kits-included-artg-legal-supply-australia&quot;&gt;Allowed test kits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.health.gov.au/sites/default/files/documents/2020/06/post-market-validation-of-the-beijing-genomics-institute-bgi-sars-cov-2-real-time-pcr-platform.pdf&quot;&gt;Post market validatio - Beijing genomics test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Time complexity</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ether nuts and bolts</title><link href="/generic/2020/05/20/ether_nuts_and_bolts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ether nuts and bolts" /><published>2020-05-20T20:48:07+10:00</published><updated>2020-05-20T20:48:07+10:00</updated><id>/generic/2020/05/20/ether_nuts_and_bolts</id><content type="html" xml:base="/generic/2020/05/20/ether_nuts_and_bolts.html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/bitcoin.pdf&quot;&gt;Bitcoint: A Peer-to-peer electronic cash system&lt;/a&gt;, 2008&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/wiki/wiki/White-Paper&quot;&gt;A Next-Generation Smart Contract and Decentralized Application Platform&lt;/a&gt;, 2013&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Bitcoint: A Peer-to-peer electronic cash system, 2008 A Next-Generation Smart Contract and Decentralized Application Platform, 2013</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">personal_bio_monitoring_higien</title><link href="/generic/2020/05/15/personal_bio_monitoring_higien.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="personal_bio_monitoring_higien" /><published>2020-05-15T11:30:43+10:00</published><updated>2020-05-15T11:30:43+10:00</updated><id>/generic/2020/05/15/personal_bio_monitoring_higien</id><content type="html" xml:base="/generic/2020/05/15/personal_bio_monitoring_higien.html">&lt;p&gt;Time complexity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Best: $O(n)$&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Average: $O(n^2)$&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Worst: $O(n^2)$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space complexity: $O(1)$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot; data-lang=&quot;python&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;bubble_sort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;len&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]:&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Time complexity</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hormon replacement therapy</title><link href="/generic/2020/05/14/hormon_replacement_therapy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hormon replacement therapy" /><published>2020-05-14T20:02:48+10:00</published><updated>2020-05-14T20:02:48+10:00</updated><id>/generic/2020/05/14/hormon_replacement_therapy</id><content type="html" xml:base="/generic/2020/05/14/hormon_replacement_therapy.html">&lt;p&gt;Hormon replacement therapy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D may be though of as a separate hormon. Dr. Rhonda Patrick - Joe Rogan 1475&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D dicreases epigenetic age of black people, who experience vitamin D deficiency leaving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C increases amount of plasma.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hormon replacement therapy</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Magic f$%&amp;amp;g wand</title><link href="/generic/2020/05/14/magic_fucking_wand.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Magic f$%&amp;g wand" /><published>2020-05-14T05:09:05+10:00</published><updated>2020-05-14T05:09:05+10:00</updated><id>/generic/2020/05/14/magic_fucking_wand</id><content type="html" xml:base="/generic/2020/05/14/magic_fucking_wand.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;magic-fg-wand&quot;&gt;Magic f$%&amp;amp;g wand&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joined new company just to realize it’s infrastructure is a smelly peace of garbage. Don’t give up. There is a way out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dreams&quot;&gt;Dreams&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was born in USSR. It sounds almost surrialistic as I’m saying it right now. Although I remember almost nothing from authentic USSR reality as I had other stuff to do in the age of 5, when soviet union collapsed. Soon after that I became a citizen of a new country called Ukraine. Back then it was struggling to find it’s place in the world. Nothing has changed since then. It keeps struggling right now just as it used to 30 years ago. And problems it is facing become bigger and bigger. Which is why I’m talking to you while being in Sydney and not in Kiev.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I acknowledge the fact, that sometimes I may sound fairly sarcastic talking about situation in Ukraine in realy it makes me sad. It’s a beautifull coutry with vast natural resources conviniently situated in a strategic position between western eaurope and Russia. In theory it should thrive. In reality it is where it is. There is not much I can do with it at this point. So instead I hallucinate and visualise what would I do if somebody gave me a magic wand. Or at least made me a dictator or a tyrant with infinite power. Just like Alexandr Lukashenko or John Lennon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(list of deeds below should rhyme with capitalism, market economy and australia relevant problems)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;I would&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;because&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;get rid of half of goverment and numerous useless ministries (like ministry of culture - for god sake, how can someone &lt;em&gt;manage a culture&lt;/em&gt;?)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;they do nothing but waste peoples taxes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;get back to 100% market economy with &lt;em&gt;0&lt;/em&gt; goverment intervention&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;no bailouts during economy crisis, people should be responsible for their own decisions&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;impose flat tax for all - 5% or something&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;people know better how to spend their money&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;introduce highest possible salary and capital punishment for judges&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;people should know they are covered in case shit hits a fan&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hard cut right here…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But of course we all know it can never happen. So I usually leave these thoughts… To come back to them later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reality&quot;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awhile ago I was introduced to oOh! infrastructure and all available technical assets. I truly belive oOh! has a vast potential as a media company. Even in this brave new world. I believe it’s on the right track with it’s audience based campaigns. In theory it should adopt to a new situation with no effort. In reality it is where it is. So instead I hallucinate and visualise what would I do if somebody gave me a magic wand. Or at least admin permissions to manage Jira, Github and AWS and ask noones permission to implement structural and process related changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;I would&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;because&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;reorganise Jira projects around areas of responsibilities, which should have one-to-one correspondence with squads, not teams&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;people that are part of these squads should know precisely, what they are responsible for&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;get rid of all legacy and abandoned Github accounts&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;all that mess makes it virtually impossible to concentrate efforts effectively&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;make the rest of them to follow a simple change management process and code structuring principles&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;many problems we have, simply stem from the fact that novody gives a shit about industry standards&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;will completely eliminate manual deployments&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;it’s unacceptable to keep wasting time moving files around&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;reorganise AWS space around “infrastructure as a code” principle and impose strict standards on technologies being used&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;at this stage our cloud environment is a wild west&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hard cut right here…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But of course we all know it can never happen. Or can it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hard cut right here…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must say, that I believe it is possible to transform a slopy collection of poorly written tools into a coherent network of components with predictable behaviour in a finite number of steps. Unfortunately, I also believe, that this transformation cannot be done by simply expecting everyone will adopt more efficient practices. Some things just have to be enforced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will try my best no to insult anyone and will be as carefull peaking my words bla bla bla… I’m joking! I don’t give a fuck on whether anyone will be insulted or not. If it sounds crazy to you, eybe it really is. Or maybe it’s simply way too different from what we got used to in oOh! media and that’s exactly what we need to really start moving in a positive direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I will try to be as granular as possible in my explanations of what has to be done. In fact this level of granularity, will make some of proposed changes looks rediculous to you. That’s ok. If at some point you feel like “What a fuck do we need this shit for?” remember - I’ve included detailed explanation of why we need it and what may be expected as a direct consequence of these actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So without further ado prepare a cup of hot beverage and fasten your seat belts. We begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;caution&quot;&gt;Caution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make no mistake thinking described changes can be implemented by explaining them to other people and expecting them to do the job. &lt;strong&gt;All&lt;/strong&gt; information in this report is already known every single person, that has at least few years of experience working in IT. There is nothing new to it. These changes won’t happen not because people are not aware of there importance, but because people lose fate, when they see a mess, that we turned our infrastructure into. Hence high churn of developers in technology.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It may seem like an unsurmountable task to implement all these changes. In reality it may be done by a 1-2 people having sufficient level of permissions and implementing changes in background in addition to their main streams of work. At least I can structure it this way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It may seem like a lot of people will be required to do the job as mentioned changes will require a diverse set of skills. In reality I can do literally everything Javascript, Python, SQL and Github related. I may need help of one single developer working on automation of AWS infrastructure as it may be difficult to switch between Javascript/Python code and Terraform scripts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It may seem like proposed way of implementing these changes is way too totalitarian and that having a company wide discussion of these changes is a good idea. It is a bad idea. This will do nothing but drag discussion in multiple directions with zero progress and no job done. We are talking about enforcing industry standards and best practices which infrastructure and tools can only benefit from. We just need to make sure some basic sanity checks are in place.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It may seem like parallelizing these changes will make it possible to implement them faster. It won’t. The whole point is to implement them one-by-one one-at-a-time. With each next stage benefiting from the previous one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whole process may seem like a blackbox. It is not. It can easily be structured in such a way, that all changes and progress are reported gradually.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zero disruption requirement can also be guaranteed easily. If changes are made gradually one-at-a-time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stage-i-rational&quot;&gt;Stage I rational&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Implement “low hanging fruit” changes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide benefits of standardization to everyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;github&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delete all abandoned repositories.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rename the rest of the repos following single standard naming convention (possibly based on responsibility areas).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make each repository to follow git flow strictly. All changes must be approved through PRs first. Later process can be scaled by gradually delegating approval permissions to squad leads.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restructure code inside repositories using one single standard (src, README, Makefile with clear entrypoints etc).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove trash files.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adopt code style checks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get rid of centralized storage of documentation in favour of project specific docs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get rid of renovation scripts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evry single project should use package mangers (npm, poetry etc) and virtual environments (poetry).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All APIs must be translated to Python.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All implemented conventions should be documented in a way, that will require no efforts from new starters to grasp.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Every shingle project must be available for running locally. All projects must run locally jointly as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dbs&quot;&gt;DBs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create centralized relational database and store &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; business data there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DB schema should be stored separately and can be change through migrations mechanism following standard change management mechanism (git flow + PRs).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transactional data should be stored in a NoSQL database (redshift). Same schema management rules apply.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NoSQL database should be populated by denormalizing business data and through pulling data from external data sources.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All ETL jobs to be implemented as Airflow DAGs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jira&quot;&gt;Jira&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jira projects reorganised around areas of responsibility.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One-to-one corresponse between area of responsibility and a squad.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Squad members to monitor their respective boards.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Standardize naming conventions for epics, labels, projects, sprints etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One iterative agile with kanban to rule them all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stage-ii-rational&quot;&gt;Stage II rational&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduce infrastructure maintenance cost.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduce services maintenance cost by making it possible to run them locally - this simplifies problem troubleshooting by an order of magnitude.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This should reduce cost of running this infrastructure as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;aws&quot;&gt;AWS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Migrate all EC2 hosted services to docker containers running K8s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stage-iii-rational&quot;&gt;Stage III rational&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eliminate inefficiencies of individual products. Eliminate code duplication. Transform slopy architecures and error prone arcitectures into:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;self documented modules&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;with type annotations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;with standardized logging both in local environments and in cloud.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;with the most appropriate tools/langs used for their respective tasks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;with clear boundaries between “our” and external services, that reliably incapsulates substanrd solutions (e.g. Quantium products)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;eliminate crazy zoo of numerous technologies by reducing their number to a small set of tools optimal for our tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some repos to be merged. Some to be split.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Magic f$%&amp;amp;g wand</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Zero consulting</title><link href="/generic/2020/05/14/zero_consulting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zero consulting" /><published>2020-05-14T05:08:55+10:00</published><updated>2020-05-14T05:08:55+10:00</updated><id>/generic/2020/05/14/zero_consulting</id><content type="html" xml:base="/generic/2020/05/14/zero_consulting.html">&lt;p&gt;Zero consulting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Potemkin vilages.
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/potemkin_valage.png&quot; alt=&quot;potemkin_image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common identical helpless motos of modern consulting businesses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Back to basics. First consulting companies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alternative decentralized approach: based on predefined facets select guaranteed experts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freemeim/semi-freemium payment schema.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Zero consulting</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">cock-a-doodle-doo</title><link href="/generic/2020/04/26/cock-a-doodle-doo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="cock-a-doodle-doo" /><published>2020-04-26T20:04:01+10:00</published><updated>2020-04-26T20:04:01+10:00</updated><id>/generic/2020/04/26/cock-a-doodle-doo</id><content type="html" xml:base="/generic/2020/04/26/cock-a-doodle-doo.html">&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time there was a man who had a long hard journey ahead of him. He was tradging along the way over boulders and through brushes when he saw a little shiny gnom with big white teeth and a black toupee sitting beside the road. He was drumming on the log with two white bones and humming oddly to himself. The little gnom said “John, why work so hard? Why walk so fast? Who knows if you’ll ever get their anyway? Come over here, I have something to show you.” So John walked off the road. He was sick of walking anyway becaused people kept throuwing sticks and stones at him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Little gnom said “I have a shiny red jewel, that I would like to sell you. Cheap!. Here it is.” And from beneath his cloak he pulled the biggest ruby, that the man has ever seen. He must have weighted a hundred pounds and shown like a sun. The gnom said “You like it? It’s an enchangthed stone. What will you offer me for it?”. And the man said “I don’t have much money, but I’ll give you everything I have”. The gnome looked displeased. So John added “I can pay some more monthly”. So the gnom accepted “Fair enough! Buy now, pay later. Sounds good for me. I’m all for the installment plan.” So the man gave a gnom all his money and promissed to pay the rest later. And a gnom walked back into the bush by the road calcking his teeth and giggling and twitching. The more the man though about this ruby and the great deal he got the happier he became. He stooded back on the road with a light heart, but soon discovered he couldn’t make much progress because a hundred pounds was a lot to carry. He said to himself “Why continue anyways? I have what I want. I’ll just stand here holding my ruby and when people walk by the can see how well i’ve already done”. So he stopped. A little while later one of his friends came along and saw him standing there. His friend said “John, why don’t you come along with me? I’ve just opened a new business and I can really use some help. Come along quick! It will be opening soon!”. John thought is sounded good  but his friend was in hurry. Besides couldn’t he see the ruby? How could he speed along beside him? Where would he put his jewel? So he said “Thanks but I have to take care of my jewel! Maybe I’ll see you later.”  His friends looked at him like he was crazy but he was trying to get somewhere quick so he just shrugged a bit and said “Ok John, see you later.” And he sped on down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little while later another friends came by and he said “John, nice to see you! I’m going back to school. Their is a lot of wonderfull things to learn, great things to do. The world is full of unsolved problems. I could use some company. Would you like to come along?”. John thought it sounded pretty good, but this friend too looked like he was in a hurry. Besides standing beside the road and holdign a jewel was tiring and he needed all the energy to keep doing that. So he said to his friend “Thanks, but I have to take care of my jewel! Is’t it beautifull? Maybe I’ll see you later.”. His friend looked at him like he was crazy. But he was trying to get somewhere quick. So he just shrugged and said “Hope everything goes allright with you. See you later.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many friends came and went and the years went by. The jewel got heavier and heavier. But the man got more and more attached to it. The only thing was nobody seemed to notice how beautifull it was. Peaople would rush by and talk about their plans and nobody had ruby as big and nobody seemd likely to get ruby as big. And you’d think that someone might have said something like at least “Nice ruby John! Should I wish one like that!”. But it has never happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then one day someone new came down the road. He was bent over and he was thin and his hair was grey. Although he didn’t look that old. He was caring a big durty rock carefully in his arms and he wasn’t making much progress. The strange figure approached and glanced up at John. Then he grinned and said “Why are you standing there so stupidly with a big ugly rock in your tired old hands? You look pretty daft. I bet you wish you had a big ruby like the one I am carrying!”. And John thought “This poor man is dilluted. He is caryying a rock! Whereas I have a ruby!”. So he said “Excuse me, sir! But you are sadly mistaken. I am the one with the jewel. I met a little gnom by this side of the road and he sold it to me. I’m still paying for it. Although not that very much. You are carrying a rock!”. A tired stranger looked annoyed “I don’t know what game you are playing, mister. You have a rock! I have a jewel! A little gnom you discribed sold it to me. And he said it was the only one. I’ve been carrying it for twenty years. And I’ll never let it go!”. And John said “But I’ve been carrying mine for twenty years too. It can’t be just a rock!”. Rock or jewel. On and on they argued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly outstepped a little gnom as if he’d never left. Only this time he wasn’t so little. He was bigger and redder and menacing and his laugh sounded like the routling of chings. “Stop arguing you two! I’ve never seen a sight so pathetic. You are carrying rocks! Both of you! And if you would ever had the sense to put them down for a second or two would have seen that! Oh well! I played a mean trick. I fill bad. SO i’m going to give you what you really deserve. The award that you really deserve”.  And John and a new stranger nodded eagerly. “Finally!” they thought. “You haven’t seen anything yet!. Through down your rocks!”. So John and a thin stranger obeyed. Each rock split down the middle when they hit the ground. Outflow a river of ravenous white worms which rushed towards the men and devoured them whole while they thrushed about and creamed. Soon nothing was left except a leg bone from each. The little gnom picked them up and walked off the road. He set down by a hollow log and started to drum. And he drummed and waited. And he hummed and odd little tune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Picture of food feeds the whole hungry clan.
The image of good makes the whole healthy man.
Why walk for miles?
Why do the work?
Just smile and smile!
Sucess after all is a quork!
Life isn’t real.
That’s the message I give.
It’s easy that way.
Plus who wants to leave?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Jordan Peterson, Maps of meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Once upon a time there was a man who had a long hard journey ahead of him. He was tradging along the way over boulders and through brushes when he saw a little shiny gnom with big white teeth and a black toupee sitting beside the road. He was drumming on the log with two white bones and humming oddly to himself. The little gnom said “John, why work so hard? Why walk so fast? Who knows if you’ll ever get their anyway? Come over here, I have something to show you.” So John walked off the road. He was sick of walking anyway becaused people kept throuwing sticks and stones at him.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">linear_regression</title><link href="/generic/2020/04/21/linear_regression.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="linear_regression" /><published>2020-04-21T19:33:43+10:00</published><updated>2020-04-21T19:33:43+10:00</updated><id>/generic/2020/04/21/linear_regression</id><content type="html" xml:base="/generic/2020/04/21/linear_regression.html">&lt;p&gt;Sources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://projecteuclid.org/download/pdf_1/euclid.aos/1176345451&quot;&gt;Gauss and the invention of least squares&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jstor.org/stable/2334569?read-now=1&amp;amp;seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&quot;&gt;Studies in the History of Probability and Statistics. XXIX: The Discovery of the Method of Least Squares&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jstor.org/stable/107429?seq=1#metadata_info_tab_contents&quot;&gt;A new method of deducing a first Approximation to the orbit of a comet from three geocentric observations&lt;/a&gt;, James Ivory, 1814&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com.au/books?id=FRcOAAAAQAAJ&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;source=gbs_ge_summary_r&amp;amp;cad=0#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;Nouvelles methodes pour la determination des orbit des cometes&lt;/a&gt;, Legendre 1805&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Sources:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Drugs</title><link href="/generic/2020/04/18/drugs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Drugs" /><published>2020-04-18T21:24:53+10:00</published><updated>2020-04-18T21:24:53+10:00</updated><id>/generic/2020/04/18/drugs</id><content type="html" xml:base="/generic/2020/04/18/drugs.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;links&quot;&gt;Links&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://druginfo.sl.nsw.gov.au/drugs/a-to-z-of-drugs&quot;&gt;Legal and illegal drugs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Statistics overview and meta study. Drugs as a “black matter” of modern seciaty (kafabe). Education is essential in any question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-personal-opinion&quot;&gt;My personal opinion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to smoke tobacco for about 5 years before quitting in the age of 20. It took me several unsuccessfull attempts before I came across brilliant book “Easy way” by Allen Carr. Back then their was a huge polarization in Ukraine as per situation with drugs. With heavy tobacco and alcohol abuse on one side and huge problems caused by heroin eddiction on the other one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started writing this article simply because I’ve accumulated a fair amount of information about drugs over drugs abuse several years. It would be fair to say, that this topic was always interesting to me due to it’s semi-legal nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the first shift in my perception was initiated by my friends, whos was deeply involved into martial arts. Thanks to him, I was able to finally hover over primitive view of some drugs as simply way of party hard and discover a spiritial component, that is largely ignored by most people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also influenced to a large extent by Peter Watts’s view on drugs, that he has brilliantly outlined in his series Rifters. This is an outstanding example of a modern “hardcore” science fiction. Though I should say, part of the reason it had such a huge influence on my perception of this topic was, that I stumbled across his book at the right period of my life. Also because Watts was able to summerise with incredible sensitivity a bunch of ideas, that were kind of floating around for some time already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not the least, many of Joe Rogan’s podcasts and his guests (Paul Stemets etc) provided me with interesting ideas regarding cannabis, DMT, cillosyben etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;possible-points-to-cover&quot;&gt;Possible points to cover&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Historical overview&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Natural form&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chemical formula&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Physiological impact&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ways of processing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hard stats (economy, health implications)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Legislation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;legal-baseline&quot;&gt;Legal baseline&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;alcohol&quot;&gt;Alcohol&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tobacco&quot;&gt;Tobacco&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;illegal-natural&quot;&gt;Illegal natural&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cannabis&quot;&gt;Cannabis&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cocaine&quot;&gt;Cocaine&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;heroin&quot;&gt;Heroin&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mushrooms&quot;&gt;Mushrooms&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;illegal-artificial&quot;&gt;Illegal artificial&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;amphetamine&quot;&gt;Amphetamine&lt;/h1&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Links</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">kayfabe</title><link href="/generic/2020/04/05/kayfabe.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="kayfabe" /><published>2020-04-05T09:26:40+10:00</published><updated>2020-04-05T09:26:40+10:00</updated><id>/generic/2020/04/05/kayfabe</id><content type="html" xml:base="/generic/2020/04/05/kayfabe.html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Folly-Fools-Logic-Deceit-Self-Deception-dp-0465027555/dp/0465027555/ref=mt_hardcover?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;me=&amp;amp;qid=&quot;&gt;“The Folly of Fools: The Logic of Deceit and Self-Deception in Human Life”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://roberttrivers.com/Robert_Trivers/Book_Reviews_files/Evolutionary%20Psycology.pdf&quot;&gt;“The Folly of Fools” - review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kayfabe - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edge.org/response-detail/11783&quot;&gt;2011 : WHAT SCIENTIFIC CONCEPT WOULD IMPROVE EVERYBODY’S COGNITIVE TOOLKIT?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">“The Folly of Fools: The Logic of Deceit and Self-Deception in Human Life” “The Folly of Fools” - review Kayfabe - 2011 : WHAT SCIENTIFIC CONCEPT WOULD IMPROVE EVERYBODY’S COGNITIVE TOOLKIT?</summary></entry></feed>